farmingdale.edu 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy

## Farmingdale State College Commitment to Privacy

At Farmingdale State College, we are committed to protecting your privacy and making it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to interact with us. We recognize that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit farmingdale.edu. You can travel through most of farmingdale.edu without giving us any information about yourself. Sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this commitment of privacy explains our online information practices. 

Farmingdale State College does not collect any _personal information_ about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail, completing the SUNY Information Request Form, or completing the online application.  
This policy is consistent with the provisions of the [Internet Security and Privacy Act](http://public.leginfo.state.ny.us/menugetf.cgi?COMMONQUERY=LAWS "Internet Security and Privacy Act"), the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. 

### Information Collected Automatically When You Visit farmingdale.edu

When visiting farmingdale.edu, Farmingdale State College automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit: 

  * The Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed our Web site
  * The type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running 
  * The Web page from which the _user_ accessed the current Web page 
  * The date and time of the _user's_ request 
  * The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page

None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute _personal information_ by the [Internet Privacy and Security Act](http://public.leginfo.state.ny.us/menugetf.cgi?COMMONQUERY=LAWS "Internet Privacy and Security Act"). The information that is collected automatically is used to improve farmingdale.edu’s content and to help Farmingdale State College understand how _users_ are interacting with its Web site. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our _users_. 

### Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Web site

The collection of information through farmingdale.edu and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the [Internet Security and Privacy Act](http://assembly.state.ny.us/leg/?cl=114&a=3 "Internet  Security and Privacy Act"). Farmingdale State College will only collect _personal information_ through farmingdale.edu or disclose _personal information_ collected through farmingdale.edu if the _user_ has consented to the collection or disclosure of such personal information. The voluntary disclosure of _personal information_ to Farmingdale State College by the _user_ , constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by Farmingdale State College for the purposes for which the _user_ disclosed the information to Farmingdale State College.  
However, Farmingdale State College may collect or disclose _personal information_ without consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of Farmingdale State College, or necessary for Farmingdale State College to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.  
Further, the disclosure of information, including _personal information_ , collected through farmingdale.edu is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law, Family Educational Rights & Privacy Act, USA Patriot Act and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.  
Farmingdale State College may disclose _personal information_ to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to Farmingdale State College’s information technology assets. 

### Information Collected When You E-mail farmingdale.edu or Complete a Transaction

During your visit to farmingdale.edu you may send an e-mail to Farmingdale State College. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to: 

  * respond to you
  * address issues you identify
  * improve this Web site

If you choose not to receive e-mail or other means of communication from Farmingdale State College, and would prefer not to in the future, you may request that you not receive communications by contacting us at privacy@farmingdale.edu.  
During your visit to farmingdale.edu you may complete a transaction such as an online survey, application or Information Request Form. The information collected by Farmingdale State College, including _personal information_ volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by Farmingdale State College and may be disclosed by Farmingdale State College for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted.  
Farmingdale State College does not knowingly collect _personal information_ from children under the age of 13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13\. _Users_ are cautioned, however, that the collection of _personal information_ submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be subject to public access. 

### Retention of Information Collected Through This Web site

The information collected through farmingdale.edu is retained by Farmingdale State College in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the New York State [Arts & Cultural Affairs Law](http://www.archives.nysed.gov/records/retention-scheduling-and-appraisal "Arts &  Cultural Affairs Law"). In general, the Internet services logs of Farmingdale State College, comprising electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of Agency services provided through farmingdale.edu, are retained for 30 days. Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the Internet privacy policy contact listed in this policy. 

### Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected Through farmingdale.edu

Any _user_ may submit a request to Farmingdale State College’s privacy officer to determine whether _personal information_ pertaining to that _user_ has been collected through farmingdale.edu. Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the _user_. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the _user_ , or similar appropriate identification. The address of the privacy officer is:

Privacy Officer  
Farmingdale State College  
2350 Broadhollow Road  
Farmingdale, New York 11735

The privacy officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the _personal information_ ; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment.

In the event that Farmingdale State College has collected _personal information_ pertaining to a _user_ through farmingdale.edu and that information is to be provided to the _user_ pursuant to the _user's_ request, the privacy officer shall inform the _user_ of his or her right to request that the _personal information_ be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of the Public Officers Law. 

### Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected Through farmingdale.edu

Farmingdale State College is strongly committed to protecting _personal information_ collected through farmingdale.edu against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently,   
Farmingdale State College limits employee access to _personal information_ collected through farmingdale.edu to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of _personal information_.  
In addition, Farmingdale State College has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of farmingdale.edu as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.  
For Web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of farmingdale.edu for all _users_ , Farmingdale State College employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage farmingdale.edu. 

### Definitions

The following definitions apply to, and appear in _italics_ , in this policy:  
_Personal information_ : For purposes of this policy, _"personal information"_ means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.  
_User_ : shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the [State Technology Law](http://public.leginfo.state.ny.us/LAWSSEAF.cgi?QUERYTYPE=LAWS+&QUERYDATA=@LLSTT+&LIST=LAW+&BROWSER=BROWSER+&TOKEN=01311561+&TARGET=VIEW "State Technology Law"). 

### Disclaimer

The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through farmingdale.edu.
